# VARUN MEHTA

**Email:** <u>er.varunkmehta@gmail.com,er.varunkmehta@ymail.com</u>

Mobile: 9860098252/9860098258

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Around 8+ years of total IT in Designs, develops, modifies, documents, tests, implements, installs and supports software applications and systems.

❖ Around 6+ Years of Experience in developing **WINFORMS using C#.net. ❖** Around 3

Years of Experience in developing **WINFORMS using VB.NET**.

❖ Around 6.2 years of experience in MS SQL SERVER & ORACLE.

Around 6.2 years of experience in MES, Hardware Interface e.g. PLC, DIO Card, Power Meter, Weight machines, Barcode Scanners & Printers etc including barcode software development, barcode creation.

- ❖ An effective communication with excellent interpersonal, logical thinking & analytical abilities.
- ❖ Have experience in Computer hardware installation & maintenance.
- ❖ Ability to express technical concepts clearly to people with non technical background.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS:

**Domain Knowledge** : Manufacturing, Banking, Retail : Winforms, C#.net, VB.NET, VB6

**Databases** : ORACLE, SOL SERVER

**Programming Methodology**: OOPs

GUI Tools : MS Visual Studio 2010, 2017

Operating Systems : Windows XP, Windows 2000 & above

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

- I am currently working as Team lead for Minans Traders Pvt Ltd. from July, 2017 till present.
- I worked as Software Developer for LG Electronics, India Pvt Ltd. under payroll of Remiel Softech Sol from Sep 21, 2012 to July, 2017.
- I worked as Software Developer at Graymatter Software Services Pvt Ltd, Bangalore from May 17, 2010 to July, 2012.

## **PROJECTS**

## Project #1.

Name: Quality Monitoring System: CODE System.

**Environment: C#.Net, Asp.net, Oracle.** 

## **Description:**

This system will be implemented for LG for all products i.e. REF, TV, AC and WM. The Purpose of this application will be real time defect identification and capturing. Defects are up to 3 level.

Level 1 - Clearly Visible (outer Body)

Level 2- Clearly Visible (inner part)

Level 3 - Not Visible.

Software facilities the operator to choose level against the defect entered by operator. After registering defect, operator have to enter the repair status, reason etc along with repair Code.

## **Responsibilities:**

❖ Gathering User Requirement, Code Development, Database design, Writing Test Cases, Implementation and application Support and Documentation.

#### Projects# 2:

**Name:Smart Control Tower** 

Environment: WINFORMS WINFORMS C#, VB6, ASP.net, Oracle

## **Description:**

This system is developed for LG?Haier for all products i.e. REF, TV, AC and WM. It was awarded best system in month of May and all subsidiaries of LG are using this system. This System developed to identifying the hidden losses means loses which are hardly able to identify. It comes under 3 Modules:

#### 1. SCT PLC DATA FETCH:

The code was written in VB.NET.NET to fetch the values from PLC and used Oracle to save values.

#### 2. SCT DISPLAY:

The code was written in C# to display the data. It has 3 Screens:

- a) Parameter: This displays the detail of temperature, Pressure and Consumption of material.
- b) Fool-Proof: This display the scanning % of product scan.
- c) Operations: The most important display, display all stages with efficiency, idle time and hidden losses.

## 3. SCT Report Download:

The webpage to download report in .CSV format for any date and any time period.

#### **Responsibilities:**

❖ Gathering User Requirement, Code Development, Database design, Writing Test Cases, Implementation and application Support and Documentation.

## **Project#3:** Name Environment: Performance Test Management: VB.NET, Oracle. <u>Description:</u>

- 1. The first part of this software is used to do 6 different type of tests on Refrigerator like Current Test, Wattage Test, Current Leakage Test etc. This program take input from the PLC-Conveyor which is attached to the machines giving reading for the appropriate current, wattage values etc. It checks if the actual result lies between lower and upper values if yes then Ok else it stop the line.
- 2. Second part is to display its result at control-tower for observation for the in-charge.
- 3. It also compares the result of this test with local matching data with G-MES result and if any mismatch found send email to all concerns.

# Responsibilities:

❖ Gathering User Requirement, Code Development, Database design, Writing Test Cases, Implementation and application Support and Documentation.

## Project#4:

Name: Asset Management System: WINFORMS C#, Oracle Environment:

## **Description:**

This software is developed for:

- 1. Asset Management: FAR-Asset Status Checking, Assigning asset.
- 2. Audit Management: Internal, External.
- 3. Provision Management: The previous months and current Provisions management.
- 4. Take care of Asset Transfer, repair etc.
- 5. Laptop Scanning System: This part senses the laptop with sensors and records the In-Out Time, when Laptop enters or goes out. If person forget to scan or try to by-pass scan, it send mail to person and his senior about this.
- 6. Attendance Management: This part save the attendance in DB from Punching Machine.
- 7. Reports: All reports from Buying Asset to Asset Discard.

## Responsibilities:

❖ Gathering User Requirement, Code Development, Database design, Writing Test Cases, Implementation and application Support and Documentation.

**Project#5:** Name : C/SKD (LG Electronics) Environment : WINFORMS C#, Oracle.

#### **Description:**

It is Complete Package bases on MES, which take care of Barcode creation, Count packed Parts, Internal barcode and Main Label Barcode. CSKD Project is based for Barcode printing and scanning applications which run on assembly It Creates barcode firstly for the parts which need to pack. After creation it count no of parts while packing, once box is full it creates a Set-ID barcode. Once we scan the Set Id the mail Barcode will print and will pasted to Box before dispatch. Also Take the Snap of Box filling Layer-by-layer, and print Picture, which also being posted on Box along with Barcode which self Explain what all parts have been packed inside Box.

#### **Responsibilities:**

❖ Gathering User Requirement, Code Development, Database design, Writing Test Cases, Implementation and application Support and Documentation.

**Project#6: Name** : ESD and Torque Check System

**Environment** : VB.NET, Oracle.

#### **Description:**

This Application is used to test Wrist and Heel band for Electrostatic Discharge leakage. This is most important application for TV and other products because if ESD is more then it may damage the Product. Also it checks the Torque of product while screwing. This was the Best-Practice for year 2015 and was implemented over all subsidiaries of LG

#### **Responsibilities:**

❖ Gathering User Requirement, Code Development, Database design, Writing Test Cases, Implementation and application Support and Documentation.

## Project#7:

Name : Auto Weight management stem

**Environment** : VB.NET, Oracle.

## **Description:**

The main purpose of this project was to check if the Product's weight is accurate or not. If Not this software will siren a Hooter and the Production Line will Stop till this product removed from Line. In home Screen, The Product barcode was scanned and behalf of that scan its actual weight, model and other information Fetched from database. On scanning of other barcode of product, we got the model of

the actual Product. After matching Model if actual weight (calculated by my software from Serial COM which is connected to Weighing Machine) in equal to database weight Test will pass else It will siren a hooter and pass a signal to DIO Card and then the production Line Will Stop with help of DIO Cards.

## Responsibilities:

Gathering User Requirement, Code Development, Database design, Writing Test Cases, Implementation and application Support and Documentation.

Project#8: Name : NCR Management System : WINFORMS C#, ASP.net, Oracle.

#### **Description:**

- The main purpose of this website is to enable use to raise NCR to concern department including the issue, effect on production, idle time etc.
- After NCR, causing dept will submit the remarks, root cause, target date etc
- Then admin level user will approve or reject the remarks based upon feasibility. If rejected it will again pass to causing dept to again fill the cause reasons.

## **Responsibilities:**

❖ Gathering User Requirement, Code Development, Database design, Writing Test Cases, Implementation and application Support and Documentation.

Project#9: Name : SQIS

**Environment** : WINFORMS C#, ASP.net, Oracle.

#### **Description:**

- The purpose of this website is to check the material quality received. The quality is being checked by various check defined. User need to check random no. of quantities out of quantity received based on logic.
- If no defect found, goods transferred to production to use goods for production.
- If Defected quantity found, return goods with RGP or without RGP based on decision from Head of dept.

#### **Responsibilities:**

❖ Gathering User Requirement, Code Development, Database design, Writing Test Cases, Implementation and application Support and Documentation.

**Project#10:** Name : ENERGY LABEL MATCHING

**Environment** : VB.net, Oracle.

## **Description:**

- The purpose of this project to make energy label pasting Fool-proof. Operator will scan the WIP barcode and according to barcode mapped energy label part code fetch from DB and Scanned Energy label will match with the Mapped barcode.
- If matches, Warranty label will be printed with the date and serial of that machine.

## **Responsibilities:**

❖ Gathering User Requirement, Code Development, Database design, Writing Test Cases, Implementation and application Support and Documentation.

**Project#11: Name : COMPRESSOR MATCHING FOOL PROOF** 

## **Environment** : WINFORMS C#, Oracle.

## **Description:**

- The purpose of this project to make Compressor assembling Fool-proof. Operator will scan the WIP barcode and according to barcode mapped compressor part code fetch from DB.
- Operator will scan the actual compressor barcode and from this Scan, Compressor Part number get fetched.
- If Scanned compressor and DB compressor matches, then Circuit Diagram (Wiring Diagram) print will came for Gas charging stage.

## **Responsibilities:**

❖ Gathering User Requirement, Code Development, Database design, Writing Test Cases, Implementation and application Support and Documentation.

Project#12: Name : FINAL VALIDATION SYSTEM

**Environment** : Vb.net,Oracle.

#### **Description:**

• The purpose of this project to stop the SET ID printing in case of any un-repair defect, any fool proof scan skip.

## **Responsibilities:**

❖ Gathering User Requirement, Code Development, Database design, Writing Test Cases, Implementation and application Support and Documentation.

Project#13: Name : AGING TEST SYSTEM-QA

**Environment** : VB, Oracle.

#### **Description:**

- The purpose of this project to keep track of different test like STLT, ELT, INLINE etc.
- Operator need to scan the Machine before putting to test area. After scanning Aging Test display
  will display the model wise count of machines in test area and display the test end date-time, so
  that operator can know the Test out time.

#### **Responsibilities:**

Gathering User Requirement, Code Development, Database design, Writing Test Cases, Implementation and application Support and Documentation

Project#14: Name : RETAIL Environment : VB6, C#

#### **Description:**

It was the complete retail software designed for Indian Retail Market, Used By

"Bharat Petroleum Corporation Limited(BPCL)" at Its Outlet In&Out. It take care of the good sold, its MRP, Stock on hand, and various Reports also.

## **Description:**

It has mainly 3 Screen as:

- a) Front End Screen. B) Back End Screen. C)Retail Screen.
- b) Retail Screen: All major operations regarding sale of goods was controlling by this. It take care of MRP, Mode of Payment etc.
- c) Back End Screen: All activities like Stock Management, Monthly, Daily and weekly reports etc was controlled by this module.

\* Responsibility: I was Responsible for creating Front-End, Modification, Enhancement and testing, Implementation and application Support and Documentation.

# **Achievements:**

- Awarded with MD-Award "GOLD" in month of February for year 2015-16.
- Awarded with MD-Award "GOLD" in month of May for year 2014-15.
- Awarded with MD-Award "SILVER" for year 2014-15.
- 6 Projects was selected as Best Practice and are being used by all subsidiaries of LG.

## **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:**

**B.Tech**. (C.S.E.) from PTU in 2008 (67%)

#### **CERTIFICATIONS:**

- **❖** Microsoft Certification : MCP-ASP.NET 2.0
- **❖** NIIT Certification :JAVA

#### PERSONAL PROFILE:

D1 - - - -

Father's Name
Date of Birth
Marital Status
Religion
: Sh. Ashok Kumar
: 11-Feb-1985
: Married
: Hindu

**Permanent Address**: P-60, Kishan Kot Amritsar, 143001

**Languages Known**: Hindi, English and Punjabi

**Hobbies** : Chess, Cricket **Passport No** : M7622979

I hereby declare that the information above is true to the best of my knowledge.

riace:	
Date:	(Varun Mehta